[MUSIC]
A covered call would be considered
by someone who would like to derive
additional income from
a long stock position.
A covered call allows
the investor to hold a long
equity position while simultaneously
receiving the premium from
selling an equal amount of
call options against it.
The covered call writer is bullish
on the stock's long term potential,
but is willing to forego a stock's
upside above the strike during the life
of the option in order to receive
the proceeds of the core premium.
The covered call writer benefits from time
decay from a reduction in volatility,
and if the stock increases its
dividend before expiration.
It should be noted that the combined
position has a similar profile to
that of a short put.
The covered call writer remains exposed
to any downside in the underlying shares,
meaning his loss potential is substantial.
[MUSIC]